PROFESSOR: You can combine the
advantages of depth-first search and
breadth-first search.
One way to combine the advantages of
depth-first and breadth-first search
is something called iterative
deepening.
The idea is you get depth-first search
space advantages with breadth-first
search's time and shallow
solution guarantees.
And the way you do this, it's super
simple, you run depth-first search but
you limit it to depth one.
That means you try everything at
depth one, but use depth-first
search to do it.
Well, if you find the solution, great.
It's a depth one, you return it.
If you didn't, then you try depth-first
search with limit two.
You know you're not going to find
a solution at depth one because
you just did that.
So if you do find the solution at
this new depth, and if you find
it, you return it.
And it's a depth two solution.
If that doesn't work, you do depth
three, and so on, until one of these
rounds returns a solution, and then
you'll know that, in fact, it's the
shallowest solution.
So you could worry, well, isn't
that kind of redundant?
I'm doing a search over and over
again but it's actually OK.
Why is it OK?
The reason it's OK is you're going to do
almost all of your work in the last
layer anyway, so everything above
that, that's just warm up.
So it's not too redundant.
In general, most of the work happens
in the lowest level.